AKASH CHOWRASIA

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

DETAILS

PHONE

9877870674

EMAIL

chowrasia.akash08@gmail.com

SKILLS

JavaScript

....

Node Js

• • • • •

React Js

Next.is

....

MongoDB

....

Git

....

openApi

....

Python

 $\bullet \bullet \bullet \bullet \circ$

C++

....

Big Data

....

Pig Latin

....

HDFS

• • • • •

Mysql • • • • • •

MSSQL

postgreSQL

....

C#

....

WPF

....

PROFILE

Working with passion for myself. I think I am a good software engineer and I always look for new target and way to make myself more better in terms of my work, my life style and my spiritual beliefs. Technically, I am quite good at MERN stack with experience of various end to end government and client project. secondly, I am also having good knowledge of scrapping using python & Selenium, Data Analysis using Pig & Hadoop, databases like MySql, MSSql & PostgreSql, openApi.

EDUCATION

B.Tech CSE, Amritsar College of engineering & technology

Amritsar

Feb 2021 — Feb 2021

CGPA: 8.01

Higher secondary, Shree Jain Vidyalaya

Kolkata

Jun 2014 — Jun 2016 Overall Marks: 74%

Secondary, Shree Maheshwary Vidyalaya

Kolkata

Jan 2004 — May 2014

Overall Marks: 75%

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software engineer, sopra steria

Noida

Aug 2021 - Present

I have been in training at sopra steria learned C# & MSSQL. Now i started working on a project based on C# & PWF.

Software Engineer, plaxonic technology

Noida

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

During my this job I worked on MENN stack while developing government projects.

INTERNSHIPS

Software Engineer Intern, Plaxonic Technologies

Noida

Oct 2020 - Jun 2021

I have worked on Python, Web-scraping, Data-Analysis, Sqlite while developing Digital Marketing Analysis tool.

I worked on MERN Stack while developing companies internal product.

LINKS

PortFolio Website

LinkedIn Profile

Github Repositories

Leetcode

LANGUAGES

English

....

Hindi

....

Bengali

....

HOBBIES

Exploring space technology Competitive Programming Listening musics

Software Development Intern, The Dimension

Aug 2020 — Oct 2020

I have worked on HTML, CSS, MYSQL while developing test series website for Internal use. I worked here as a Project Lead.

Technical content writer, Geeksforgeeks

virtual

Kolkata

Nov 2021 - Present

I have written several articles based on Bid Data, pig & Hadoop, competitive coding for GeeksforGeeks.

PROJECTS HIGHLIGHT

Delhi Jal Board Dosing System

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021

I am worked on Dashboard dosing & live data flow from IOT sensors in this project using **Next.js** and **Node.js**.

MyCovidHelpLine

Apr 2021 - Apr 2021

This Project was Built in **Next.js** and **Node.js** in a weak at plaxonic. This was developed for instant requirement to supply the important things to the needy people around Delhi NCR area.

KangraCare

May 2021 - Jun 2021

This was a government project for medical relief at Plaxonic in **Node.js** & **React.js.** view.

I was working on review and deployment side of the project.

Quiz Game

May 2018 - Dec 2018

This was my first ever console based Turbo C++ project written in **C++** with all required features for admin & candidates with some special functionality like Timer, candidate time flexibility, certificates decorated with musics and colors. <u>View</u>

Impulsive shopper

Oct 2019 - Dec 2019

This is an end to end sample Automation project written in **Python** & **selenium** featured with automatic shopping according to season Implemented over test shopping website. <u>View</u>

Baltimore Crime Analysis

Feb 2020 - Jul 2020

This project consists of several case studies on crime record of Baltimore (USA) written in **Pig Latin** Implemented over **HDFS** which may help the security system to improve crime prediction rate. <u>View</u>

Billing Guide

Feb 2020 - May 2020

This project was a borrow management system for shopkeepers written in Python uses CSV file to store data at local system. <u>View</u>

Library Commander

Aug 2018 - Nov 2018

This was a Command based **Python** project used for managing book library operations. **MySQL** is used as the database, featured with 4N normalization. <u>View</u>

Smarty

Feb 2019 - Jul 2019

This was a research based Data Science personal Assistant for linux users which is able to manage all the operations of the system on voice command like media playing from system & Internet, opening PDF, downloading media, searching files, operating projects, system status, managing files, making video logs etc. view

Viveedh

Dec 2020 - Feb 2021

This was a Linux based networking project, used for managing multiple LAN systems at a time with the different jobs, developed using **TMUX**, **React**, **Python** & **SQLite**. view

Nariyal Pani Wala

Noida

Mar 2022 - May 2022

This is an end to end business idea based project to serve **coconuts** to people at their home with the help of mobile apps. I successfully developed complete Back-end and web Dashboard in this project.

PUBLICATIONS

A case study on crime Dataset of Baltimore, Maryland(USA)

ICDSML

Sep 2020

This is a research paper published in **International conference of Data Science & Machine Learning**. I had played the roll of main author Into the Paper. This is based on Big Data Analytic using Hadoop and PigLatin. I have Analyzed and fetched some important facts related to crime in Baltimore city. <u>View</u> at **INDEX No. 62**

Technical Articles

GeeksforGeeks

Apr 2020

Published Four Articles on different topics related to various technologies. click

Documentary Review "Role of Technical Doctrines in Space Science"

International conference on FCDSEGS

Oct 2021

I have published this conference paper expressing and recognizing Artificial intelligence Roles in Space Science.